IUDITH T CHATIZA

Motivated natural resource conservationist, also passionate about technology and how it contributes to climate change. I have worked in conservation for more than five years with the aim to mitigate climate change. Currently pursuing an honors degree in Computer Science.

CONTACT DETAILS



ichatiza17@alustudent.com



+250784796599



f Kigali, Rwanda



EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science African Leadership University; Kigali, Rwanda, (September 2017 - May 2021)

Relevant Courses:

Programming 1 (Python); Programming II (Java); Database Management Systems; Discrete Mathematics; Database Systems; Foundational Mathematics for Computing; Website Development; Data Structures and Algorithms, Computer Networks, Human Computer Interaction, Technologies Societies, Systems Programming, Software Development and ENgineering

Certificate in Leadership Core African Leadership University; Kigali, Rwanda (September 2017 - May 2018)

Relevant Courses:

Entrepreneurial Leadership: Data and Decisions; Communicating for Impact; Project Management

Actuarial Analyst Certification Certified Actuarial Analyst Global; Kigali, **Rwanda (October 2018 - Present)**

Relevant papers taken yet: CAA Global Module 0

WORK EXPERIENCE

REMOTE WEB DESIGNER

Kigali Arena, Rwanda: Jan 2019 - Present

Designed a web application for the Kigali Arena in a group of 5 and the project was approved by the Ministry of Sports Rwanda Working with Ministry of Rwanda in a group of 8 on designing and implementing an online presence of Kigali Arena

GRANT WRITING INTERN

East African Power (EAP), Rwanda: August 2019 - February 2020

Perform independent research on market conditions, and develop business plans and reports for upcoming utility-sized mini hydropower projects in East Africa

Research and discover new grants which fund the company's programs and services and create funding plans and report to EAP Directors

CONSERVATION INTERN

Kitabi Ecocentre Nyungwe, Rwanda: May 2019 - August 2019

Proposed eco friendly recreational services to be implemented at the Ecocentre to improve customer engagement as well as the employees outside of work and managed to implement a volleyball pitch which we set up with the help of two other interns and made a traditional ball with the use of available natural resources and is up and running at the ecocentre which has improved customer to employee relationships as well as engagement at the ecocentre.

Discovered a new trail in the Nyungwe Buffer zone which is called the Elephant Trail which leads to a small river where Mountain Elephants used to go drink water before extinction in Nyungwe National Park which has increased the company's revenues by 5% as many people are paying to hike in that trail.

Created a website for the eco-tourism company which helped them to have an online presence and as well made it easy for their international clients to start booking online

CONSERVATION INTERN

Forestry Commission, Bulawayo, Zimbabwe:July 2018 - August 2018

Worked in the District Conservator's office accounting for all forestry produce permits which gave the District conservator and the ecologist time to focus on improving policies regarding forestry conservation. Wrote comprehensive weekly, monthly, quarterly and half yearly reports for the Bulawayo station, District and Province to be sent to the

JUDITH T CHATIZA

SKILLS

Google Suit Teamwork
Research Project
Management Data analysis
Accounting Design Thinking

INTEREST(S)

Natural Resource Conservation Women and Youth Empowerment Regional Integration Child Rights Activism

LANGUAGE (S)

English (proficient)
Shona (native)
Ndebele (beginner)
Kiswahili (beginner)
Kinyarwanda (beginner)

REFERRALS

Dr Gaidi Faraj
Dean of Faculty & Academics
African Leadership University
Contact: gfaraj@alueducation.com

Ms. Nokuthaba Nyathi District Conservator Bulawayo Forestry Commission Zimbabwe Contacts: nokuthabanyathi@gmail.com

Mr Phillip Kuvawoga
Wildlife Management Specialist
World Wildlife Fund; Zimbabwe
Contacts: philmadawo@gmail.com

Minister of Environment and Natural Resource management. This had the Minister paying a visit to the province for a congratulatory ceremony to Matabeleland North Province for highly performing in the first half of 2018 amongst all the provinces.

Took care of accounting books for all forestry produce sales and granted forestry produce permits at the Bulawayo District Office which increased income from forestry produce by 5% and reduced forestry produce poaching cases by 7% in the third quarter of the year.

Managed the District Conservator's calendar which included filing for forests extension offices needs on his behalf which helped him address office needs on time and improved the deliverables from Forest Extension Officers as they felt engaged

MATHEMATICS TUTOR

Chiedza Children's Home: November 2016 - July 2017

Worked in a group of fifteen tutoring more than twenty students each that had scores below 50% once every week for two hours which increased mathematics pass rate by 30%.

Created content and designed a class to tutor in mathematics sessions of more than twenty students per session which increased mathematics pass rate by 30%.

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

RECRUITER

Education Matters, Zimbabwe: March 2017 - Present

Works in a group of 10 people recruitment team that received more than 1500 applications from all over Zimbabwe for USAP and selects 50 students who will later be narrowed down to enroll 40 students after being interviewed. Also facilitates a college fair for students and parents with students who are coming to African Leadership University or aspire to apply to the school in the future every year.

AMBASSADOR

African Leadership University School of Wildlife Conservation, Rwanda: October 2017 - Present

Creates marketing content for ALU School of Wildlife Conservation

Model for African Leadership University School Of Wildlife Conservation videos and marketing pictures which has helped spread the word of scholarships available for masters students, special women in conservation and helped push through some of their social media hashtags like #sheleadsconservation.

JUDITH T CHATIZA